A Finding Aid to the Everett Shinn Collection, 1877-1958, in the Archives of American Art AAA.shinever
Archives of American Art
Everett Shinn collection
1877-1958
AAA.shinever
Archives of American Art
3 Linear feet
The collected papers of Everett Shinn measure 3.0 linear feet and date from 1877 to 1958. Found within the papers are biographical material; correspondence with friends and colleagues; personal business records; art work, including two sketchbooks of designs for Belasco's Stuyvesant Theatre; notes and writings; eight scrapbooks; printed material; and numerous photographs of Shinn, his colleagues, and his work.
Everett Shinn
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The bulk of the Everett Shinn collection was acquired via purchase from art dealer Thurston Thatcher between 1958-1964. Art collector Howard Lipman donated additional material in 1962. Five negatives of Shinn's work were donated in 1969 by Dr. Milton Luria, an acquaintance of Shinn's son, Davidson. The photograph of Everett Shinn, John Sloan, and Robert Henri was donated on an unknown date by an unidentified donor. The handwritten draft of Shinn's play Hazel Weston or More Sinned Against Than Usual was acquired via auction purchase in 2011.
Related Archival Materials note
Additional Everett Shinn papers are available at the Helen Farr Sloan Library, Delaware Art Museum, Wilmington, Delaware.
Existence and Location of Copies note
The bulk of this collection was digitized in 2011 and is available on the Archives of American Art's website. Materials which have not been scanned include photographs of works of art; duplicates; blank pages in bound volumes; blank versos of photographs; readily available copies of printed material, and oversized material too large to be scanned. In some cases, publications have had their covers, title pages, and relevant pages scanned.
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original papers requires an appointment.
Biographical/Historical note
Everett Shinn (1876-1953) was a painter, muralist, illustrator, and theatrical scene designer who worked primarily in New York City. Shinn was a member of "The Eight," a group of painters known for their realistic portrayal of American urban life.
Everett Shinn was born on November 6, 1876 in Woodstown, New Jersey, the son of Isaiah and Josephine Ransley Shinn. He attended Quaker schools until 1890 when he went to the Spring Garden Institute in Philadelphia, studying engineering and industrial design until 1893.
Shinn enrolled at the Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts between 1893 and 1897. During this time he was hired as an artist-reporter for the Philadelphia Press, the Inquirer, and the Ledger. He also forged his friendships with painters George Luks, John Sloan, William J. Glackens, and Robert Henri, all future members of "The Eight."
Shinn moved to New York City in 1897 and quickly found employment as an illustrator for the newspaper The World. In 1898, he married Florence Scovel, the first of his four wives. In 1900, he traveled to England and France, and was later employed by Harper's Weekly. Shinn befriended decorator Elsie De Wolf and architect Stanford White, and designed and executed murals for the homes of their clients. Shinn created eighteen mural panels for David Belasco's Stuyvesant Theatre that opened in 1907, and murals for the Council Room of the Trenton, New Jersey City Hall in 1911. His most notable murals were created for the Oak Room of New York's Plaza Hotel in the 1940s.
In 1908, Shinn participated in the seminal group exhibition of "The Eight" at Macbeth Gallery. In 1911, he was included in the Exhibition of Independent Artists, and was invited to send works to the International Exhibition of Modern Art, better known as the Armory Show, in 1913, but for an unknown reason, declined. Shinn exhibited regularly and his works are in the collections of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, the Delaware Art Museum, the Art Institute of Chicago, and the Whitney Museum of American Art, among others.
Throughout his career Shinn was fascinated by the theater and the act of performance, which he made the subject of many of his works. He also wrote, directed, and performed in his own plays. Between 1917 and 1920, Shinn worked as an art director for Sam Goldwin at Goldwyn Pictures. He also worked for Inspiration Pictures from 1920 to 1923, and for William Randolph Hearst at Cosmopolitan Pictures in 1923. He divorced Florence Scovel in 1912, and married Corinne Baldwin in 1913, with whom he had two children, Janet and Davidson. He divorced again in 1921, married Gertrude Chase in 1924, and divorced again in 1932. In 1933, Shinn married his fourth wife, Paula Downing; they divorced in 1942.
From 1935 to 1939, he covered a murder trial for the Boston Traveler, exhibited his work at the Whitney Museum of American Art, and won a prize for watercolor at an exhibition at the Chicago Art Institute. In the 1940s Shinn participated in exhibitions at the Brooklyn Museum, Carnegie Institute in Pittsburgh, Philadelphia Museum of Art, and at the American-British Art Center. In 1949, Shinn was made an Academician of the National Academy of Design, and in 1951, he was inducted into the American Academy of Arts and Letters.
Everett Shinn died on May 1, 1953 in New York City.
Scope and Contents note
The collected papers of Everett Shinn measure 3.0 linear feet and date from 1877 to 1958. Found within the papers are biographical material; correspondence with friends and colleagues; personal business records; art work, including two sketchbooks of designs for Belasco's Stuyvesant Theatre; notes and writings; eight scrapbooks; printed material; and numerous photographs of Shinn, his colleagues, and his work.
Biographical material includes miscellaneous biographical accounts and a membership certificate from the American Watercolor Society.
Correspondence consists of letters from Shinn's friends and colleagues, primarily from author Poultney Bigelow. There are also letters from decorator Elsie De Wolfe, dramatist Clyde Fitch, and artists Charles Dana Gibson, William Glackens, and George Luks, whose letters are illustrated. There are scattered letters from A. Stirling Calder, Theodore Dreiser, Robert Henri, Ernest Lawson, Julia Marlowe, Claude Rains, Ruth Warrick, Alexander Woollcott, and Mahonri Young.
Personal business records consist of two account books recording art work used in publications and loaned for exhibitions, and miscellaneous invoices.
Artwork consists of two sketchbooks of designs for the Stuyvesant Theatre murals and miscellaneous drawings by Shinn. Artwork by others, including H. B. Eddy, James Ben Ali Haggin, Colonel Hegan, Oliver Henfold, George Luks, and Philip Nolan, consist primarily of caricatures.
Notes and writings include a handwritten draft of Shinn's play Hazel Weston or More Sinned Against Than Usual, notes for a book on art, poems, and typescripts by Shinn including "Plush and Cut Glass," a book about George Luks.
Eight scrapbooks primarily contain clippings. Scrapbook 2 contains clippings, exhibition catalogs, a note from Stuart Benson, an illustrated postcard from Ed, and scattered photographs.
Additional printed material is primarily comprised of clippings, but there are also exhibition announcements and catalogs for Shinn, reproductions of art work, booklets, and miscellaneous printed material. Rare programs for plays written by Shinn list cast members, including Wilfred Buckland, Edith Glackens, William J. Glackens, James Ben Ali Haggin, Robert Henri, J. E. Laub, Thomas Newell Metcalf, James M. Preston, Florence Scovel Shinn, and John Sloan.
Numerous photographs are found within the collection and depict Shinn as a boy, in various Philadelphia newspaper offices, in costume for stage performances, at the easel, and with colleagues, including Robert Henri and John Sloan. Photographs of colleagues also include author Poultney Bigelow, decorator Elsie De Wolfe, portrait painter James Ben Ali Haggin, actress Julia Marlowe, and Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts classmates William Glackens and Florence Scovel. There are also photographs of Shinn's residences, exhibition installations, set designs and stagings of plays, murals, and other art work.
Arrangement note
The collection is arranged as 8 series:
Series 1: Biographical material, 1953 (Box 1; 2 folders)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1899-1952 (Box 1, 4; 61 folders)
Series 3: Personal business records, 1898-1928 (Box 1; 3 folders)
Series 4: Artwork, 1893-1928 (Box 1, 4, OV 6; 10 folders)
Series 5: Notes and writings, 1922-1951 (Box 1; 9 folders)
Series 6: Scrapbooks, 1898-1952 (Box 1, 2, 4, BV 5; 21 folders)
Series 7: Printed material, 1894-1958 (Box 2, 4; 21 folders)
Series 8: Photographs, 1877-1950 (Box 2-4, OV 7; 1.3 linear feet)
Bigelow, Poultney, b. 1855; Calder, Alexander Stirling, 1870-1945; De Wolfe, Elsie, 1865-1950; Dreiser, Theodore, 1871-1945; Eddy, H. B.; Fitch, Clyde, 1865-1909; Gibson, Charles Dana, 1867-1944; Glackens, William J., 1870-1938; Grove, William; Haggin, Ben Ali, 1882-1951; Hegan, Colonel; Henfold, Oliver; Henri, Robert, 1865-1929; Lawson, Ernest, 1873-1939; Luks, George Benjamin, 1867-1933; Marlowe, Julia, 1865-1950; Nolan, Philip; Rains, Claude, 1889-1967; Sale, Chic; Scovel, Florence; Sloan, John, 1871-1951; Warrick, Ruth; Washington Park Studio.; Wollcott, Alexander; Young, Mahonri Mackintosh, 1877-1957; Illustrated letters; Illustrators--New York (State)--New York; Notes; Painters--New York (State)--New York; Painting, American; Photographs; Poems; Scrapbooks; Sketchbooks; Stage designers--New York (State)--New York; Theaters--Stage-setting and scenery
- Biographical Material, 1953; Series 1; 2 Folders Box 1
  Scope and Contents note
  Biographical material consists of miscellaneous biographical accounts and a membership certificate from the American Watercolor Society.
  Existence and Location of Copies note
  This series has been scanned in its entirety.
  - Miscellaneous Biographical Accounts, circa 1920-1950 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Membership Certificate from the American Watercolor Society, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1899-1952; Series 2; 61 Folders Box 1, 4
  Correspondence primarily consists of letters from Shinn's friends and colleagues, including Poultney Bigelow, Elsie De Wolfe, Clyde Fitch, Charles Dana Gibson, William Glackens, and George Luks. There are scattered letters from A. Stirling Calder, Theodore Dreiser, Robert Henri, Ernest Lawson, Julia Marlowe, Claude Rains, Ruth Warrick, Alexander Woollcott, and Mahonri Young.
  - Art Institute of Chicago, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bigelow, Poultney, circa 1920-1950 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bigelow, Poultney, 1920-1932 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Oversized material housed in Box 4, F1
  - Bigelow, Poultney, 1933-1934 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bigelow, Poultney, 1935; 3 Folders (Box 1, Folder 7-9)
  - Bigelow, Poultney, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bigelow, Poultney, 1937; 3 Folders (Box 1, Folder 11-13)
  - Bigelow, Poultney, 1938; 2 Folders (Box 1, Folder 14-15)
  - Bigelow, Poultney, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Bigelow, Poultney, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Bigelow, Poultney, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Bigelow, Poultney, 1942; 2 Folders (Box 1, Folder 19-20)
  - Bigelow, Poultney, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Bigelow, Poultney, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Bigelow, Poultney, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Bigelow, Poultney, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Bigelow, Poultney, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Bigelow, Poultney, 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Bonner, Mollie, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Burnham, F.R., circa 1920-1950 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - B, Miscellaneous, 1952; 1906; 1912 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Calder, A. Stirling, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Coral Gables Corporation, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Cornwall, E., undated; 1915 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Cox, May, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - C, Miscellaneous, 1918; undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - De Wolfe, Elsie, 1900; undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Delineator, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Engel, Michael M., 1942 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Fitch, Clyde, 1899; undated; 2 Folders (Box 1, Folder 38-39)
  - Gibson, Charles Dana, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Glackens, William, circa 1920-1950 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Gruger, Frederic R., 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Haggeman, Julia, circa 1920-1950 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Henri, Robert, 1904; undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Horace Liveright Theatrical Productions, 1926-1927 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Irwin, Wallace, circa 1920-1950 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - John C. Winston Co., 1941 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Kelly, Hugh Williamson, circa 1920-1950 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Lawson, Ernest, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Lindeberg, H.T., circa 1920-1950 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Luks, George, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Mahonri, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Marlowe, Julia, 1902 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - R, Miscellaneous, undated; 1927 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Sallsten, William, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Street, Julian, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - S, Miscellaneous, undated; 1928 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Tevis, Sally, circa 1920-1950 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Warrick, Ruth, circa 1920-1950 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Woollcott, Alexander, 1935; 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - W, Miscellaneous, 1909; undated (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Unidentified Correspondents, 1918; 1920; 1937; 1952; 1915 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Six Oversized Letters from Poultney Bigelow, 1932-1939 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Scanned with Box 1, F5, F12, F15-16
- Personal Business Records, 1898-1928; Series 3; 3 Folders Box 1
  Personal business records consist of account books recording art work used in publications and loaned for exhibitions, and miscellaneous invoices.
  - Account Book of Art Work Used in Publications and Loaned for Exhibitions, 1898-1911 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Account Book of Art Work Loaned to Various Exhibitions, 1899-1912 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Miscellaneous Invoices, 1915-1928 (Box 1, Folder 65)
- Artwork, 1893-1928; Series 4; 10 Folders Box 1, 4, OV 6
  Artwork consists of two sketchbooks of designs for the Stuyvesant Theatre murals and miscellaneous drawings by Shinn and others, including H. B. Eddy, James Ben Ali Haggin, Colonel Hegen, Oliver Henfold, George Luks, and Philip Nolan.
  - Sketchbooks of Drawings for Belasco's Stuyvesant Theatre Murals by Everett Shinn, circa 1900s (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Miscellaneous Drawings by Everett Shinn, circa 1893-1928 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    Oversized material housed in Box 4, F2 and OV 6
  - Drawing by H. B. Eddy, circa 1893-1928 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    Oversized material housed in Box 4, F2
  - Drawing by James Ben Ali Haggin, circa 1893-1928 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Drawing by Colonel Hegan of Kentucky (Related to Alice Hegan Rice), circa 1893-1928 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Drawing by Oliver Henfold of Robert Reed, circa 1893-1928 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Drawing Gathering News by George Luks, circa 1893-1928 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Drawing by Philip Nolan, circa 1893-1928 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Four Oversized Drawings by Everett Shinn, circa 1893-1928 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Scanned with Box 1, F67
  - Oversized Drawing by H. B. Eddy, circa 1893-1928 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Scanned with Box 1, F68
  - Oversized Drawing by Everett Shinn, circa 1893-1928 (Box OV 6)
- Notes and Writings, 1922-1951; Series 5; 9 Folders Box 1
  Notes and writings include a handwritten draft of Shinn's play Hazel Weston or More Sinned Against Than Usual, notes for a book on art, poems, and typescripts by Shinn including "Plush and Cut Glass," a book about George Luks.
  - Handwritten draft of play Hazel Weston or More Sinned Against Than Usual by Everett Shinn, August 1951 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Notes for a Book on Art by Everett Shinn, circa 1949-1951; 3 Folders (Box 1, Folder 75-77)
  - Typescript, "A Dream," by Everett Shinn, circa 1920-1950 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Typescript, "Francois Coupe," by Everett Shinn, circa 1920-1950 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Typescript, "Gego Gorgo," by Everett Shinn, circa 1920-1950 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Typescript about George Luks, "Plush and Cut Glass" by Everett Shinn, circa 1920-1950 (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Poems by Everett Shinn, 1922; circa 1920-1950 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Miscellaneous Writings by Everett Shinn, circa 1920-1950 (Box 1, Folder 83)
- Scrapbooks, 1891-1908; Series 6; 21 Folders Box 1, 2, 4, BV 5
  Eight scrapbooks primarily contain clippings. Scrapbook 2 contains clippings, exhibition catalogs, a note from Stuart Benson, an illustrated postcard from Ed, and scattered photographs.
  The bulk of this series has been scanned. Oversized materials larger than the scanning bed have not been scanned.
  - Scrapbook 1, 1898-1908 (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Scrapbook 2, loose items, 1898-1952; 4 Folders (Box 1, Folder 85-88)
    Oversized material housed in BV 5; partially scanned
  - Scrapbook 3, 1907-1917 (Box 1, Folder 89)
    Oversized material housed in Box 4, F3
  - Scrapbook 4, 1910-1911 (Box 1, Folder 90)
    Oversized material housed in Box 4, F4
  - Scrapbook 5, loose items, 1910-1911 (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Scrapbook 5, 1910-1911 (Box 1, Folder 92)
    Oversized material housed in Box 4, F5
  - Scrapbook 6, 1919-1930; 2 Folders (Box 1, Folder 93-94)
    disbound
  - Scrapbook 7, 1923-1925 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Disbound
  - Scrapbook 8, Concerning the Trial at Dedham Courthouse, loose items, 1934; 4 Folders (Box 2, Folder 2-5)
    Oversized material housed in Box 4, F6
  - Oversized Scrapbook 3, 1907-1917 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Scanned with Box 1, F89
  - Oversized Scrapbook 4, 1910-1911 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Scanned with Box 1, F90
  - Oversized Scrapbook 5, 1910-1911 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Scanned with Box 1, F92
  - Oversized Scrapbook 8, Concerning the Trial at Dedham Courthouse, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    Scanned with Box 2, F5
  - Oversized Scrapbook 2, 1898-1952 (Box BV 5)
    Oversized material from Box 1, F88
- Printed Material, 1894-1958; Series 7; 21 Folders Box 2, 4
  Printed material includes clippings, exhibition announcements and catalogs for Shinn, reproductions of art work, booklets, and miscellaneous printed material. Programs for plays list cast members, including Wilfred Buckland, Edith Glackens, William J. Glackens, James Ben Ali Haggin, Robert Henri, J. E. Laub, Thomas Newell Metcalf, James M. Preston, Everett Shinn, Florence Scovel Shinn, and John Sloan.
  The bulk of this series has been scanned. Booklets and miscellaneous items have not been scanned.
  - Clippings, circa 1900-1950; 4 Folders (Box 2, Folder 6-9)
  - Clippings, 1904-1910 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Clippings, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Clippings, 1912-1914 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Oversized material housed in Box 4, F7 and OV6
  - Clippings, 1928-1939 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Clippings, 1943-1947 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Clippings, 1951-1958 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Oversized material housed in Box 4, F7
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs for Everett Shinn, 1943-1946 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Reproductions of Art Work, circa 1900-1950 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Oversized material housed in Box 4, F8
  - Reproductions of Art Work for Belasco's Stuyvesant Theatre, circa 1900-1950 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Programs for Plays, circa 1900-1950; 1894 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Actors' Fund of America Benefit Programs, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Booklet Daniel Frohman, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Booklet The Illustrators' Sketch Book, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Booklet U.S. Army in Action, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, circa 1940-1952 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Six Oversized Clippings, 1913; 1914; 1958 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    Scanned with Box 2, F12, F15
  - Three Oversized Reproductions of Art Work, circa 1900-1950 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    Scanned with Box 2, F17
  - Oversized Program for Play Lucy Moore: The Prune Hater's Daughter, circa 1900-1950 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    Scanned with Box 2, F19
  - Oversized Brochure for Illustrated Books, circa 1900-1950 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    Scanned with Box 2, F24
  - Oversized Sign Advertising Everett Shinn's Coverage of the Millen-Faber Trial, circa 1900-1950 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Two Oversized Clippings, 1912-1914 (Box OV 6)
    Scanned with Box 2, F12
- Photographs, 1877-1950; Series 8; 1.3 Linear feet Box 2-4, OV 7
  Arrangement note
  Photographs are arranged chronologically by image content.
  Photographs are of Shinn as a boy, in various Philadelphia newspaper offices, in costume for stage performances, at the easel, and with colleagues, including Robert Henri, John Sloan. Photographs of colleagues also include author Poultney Bigelow, decorator Elsie De Wolfe, portrait painter James Ben Ali Haggin, actress Julia Marlowe, and Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts classmates William Glackens and Florence Scovel. There are also photographs of Shinn's residences, exhibition installations, set designs and stagings of plays, murals, and other art work.
  The bulk of this series has been scanned. Tintypes, duplicates, and reproductions of artwork have not been scanned.
  - Photographs of Everett Shinn and of Shinn with Friends and Colleagues, circa 1877-1892; 3 Folders (Box 2, Folder 25-27)
  - Photographs of Everett Shinn with Friends in Philadelphia Newspaper Office, circa 1893; 2 Folders (Box 2, Folder 28-29)
  - Photographs of Everett Shinn in Costume, 1894 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Photographs of Everett Shinn in Philadelphia Newspaper Office, 1895-1896 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Photographs of Everett Shinn, circa 1896 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Photographs of Everett Shinn and of Shinn with Friends and Colleagues, 1897; 5 Folders (Box 2, Folder 33-37)
  - Photograph of Everett Shinn with Robert Henri, and John Sloan, 1897 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Photographs of Everett Shinn in Robert Henri's Studio, circa 1897 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Photographs of Everett Shinn in John Sloan's Studio, 1898 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Photographs of Everett Shinn, circa 1900-1950; 3 Folders (Box 2, Folder 41-43)
    Oversized material housed in OV 7
  - Photographs of Everett Shinn's Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts Classmates, Grace G. Ryder, Florence Scovel, Anna L. Griffith, Elizabeth Hunter, Francis Vaux Wilson, William J. Glackens, J. M. Preston, and Charles E. Plumb, 1894 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Photographs of Poultney Bigelow, circa 1940-1950 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Photograph of Arnold Daly, 1902 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Photographs of Elsie De Wolfe, 1900-1903 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Photograph of Richard Duffy, circa 1900-1920 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Photographs of James Ben Ali Haggin, circa 1900-1920 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Photograph of Robert Henri, 1897 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Photographs of Julia Marlowe, 1899-1905; 2 Folders (Box 2, Folder 51-52)
  - Photograph of John Sloan and Frank Taylor in Costume, 1894 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Photographs of Unidentified Friends and Colleagues, circa 1900-1930 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Photographs of the Washington Square House, circa 1900-1930; 2 Folders (Box 2, Folder 55-56)
  - Photographs of Unidentified Buildings, circa 1900-1930; 3 Folders (Box 2, Folder 57-59)
  - Photographs of Exhibition Installations, circa 1944-1946 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Photographs of Set Design and Staging of Play about the Revolutionary War, circa 1910-1940; 6 Folders (Box 2, Folder 61-66)
  - Photographs of Set Design for The Prince and the Pauper, circa 1900-1940 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Photographs of Set Design and Staging of Play Benjamin Franklin at the Court of Louis XVI, circa 1900-1940 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Photographs of Set Design for The Dump, 1934-1940 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Photographs of Murals for the Plaza Hotel Oak Bar, circa 1900-1940 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Photographs of Murals for David Belasco's Stuyvesant Theatre, circa 1900-1940 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Photographs of Studies for Decoration of City Hall, Trenton, New Jersey, circa 1900-1940 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    Oversized material housed in Box 4, F9